Stanislav Ashykhmin



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Started from 5, and then I managed a team of 300 employees.

Overall 2 years as a middle QA engineer. Project: LTE chips for IoT.

Overall 1-year experience as Business Analytic. E-commerce projects.

Overall 15+ years' experience in sales in managerial positions.

My position was between Chief Operating Officer and Head of Sales for foreign markets. I also covered part of responsibilities in business development for new products in the developing USA region. I have a lot of experience in business trips and negotiations with customers on both sides of the Atlantic Ocean.

Passionately love and play video games for over 30 years. Started with Doom in 1993, continue to play shooters, strategy, sim racing, RTS. Troll 80 lvl. in online rpg. \bigcirc

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: ashykhmin.s@gmail.com

Cell: +49 16 093 479 387 Location: Cologne, Germany

Nationality: Ukrainian Birth date: 27.01.1982

LANGUAGES

💳 Ukrainian – native

Russian – native

ﷺ English − advanced

EXPERIENCE

Middle QA Engineer

GlobalLogic, a Hitachi Group Company

Jan, 2021 - present time (1-year 10 month)

- Requirements analysis and test documentation creation;
- Specification based and change related testing;
- Troubleshooting and investigation;
- Logs analysis and White box testing;
- Automation test redaction/fixing using Python;
- Issue tracking/team collaboration systems: JIRA, Confluence, Bugzilla, Redmine, SAP, ERP;
- Version Control: Git, Gitlab, GitHub;
- CI/CD Continuous integration/Continuous delivery: fundamentals of Jenkins, TeamCity, Docker, Azure, AWS;
- Presenting business or marketing opportunities to the Company's executives and management;
- Linux Administration and Lan technologies. Network diagnostics;
- Customer support;
- Agile software development: Waterfall, Scrum understanding of Kanban;
- Client/Server Architecture. RPC servers;
- Trainings for newcomers (I trained 5 interns in 2021).

Business analyst

ITLight

Apr, 2020 - Jan, 2021 (9 months)

- Business analysis and Requirement's analysis (elicitation, estimation);
- User stories definition;
- Prototyping, Wireframing and BPMN, UML modeling;
- Gap/risks analysis;
- Negotiation with stakeholders (customers and their representatives);
- Creation of technical documentation;
- Project backlog management;
- Manage and track the status of the requirements throughout the project lifecycle;
- Translation of business requirements to software using BDD acceptance criteria.

Head of Export Sales (US, EU)

LLC METINVEST-HOLDING

Jan, 2018 - Apr, 2020 (2 years)

- Managing a specialized business for creating modern parts for railway cars;
- Negotiations with international companies in 20 different countries;
- Development of an agent network in export regions (Asia, EU, USA, CIS, North Africa, ROW);
- New product development (EU and USA markets);
- Preparation of an annual business plan, analyze consolidation of Customer base development in Europe, America;
- Payment and delivery terms negotiation;
- Maintaining sales and delivery records, quarterly and annual sales forecasts.

From 2002 to 2018, I worked in senior sales positions in the largest steel companies in Ukraine. But I have always been interested in the field of IT, because I have always loved science fiction and everything that develops technology.

EDUCATION

Oct, 2021 - Jan, 2022 Hillel IT School, Business Analysis (Certificate Grade: Excellent)

Apr, 2020 - Nov, 2020 QA Light School, Quality Assurance Ultimate Course

2005 - 2010 Donetsk National University, Master's in International Economics

OTHER SKILLS

- Business negotiations
- Deep analytical skills
- People management
- Analysis and development of markets

HOBBY

- Storytelling
- Simulator racing games
- Traveling
- Fitness